

CONTACT ME

+4915753936480/

+264852473265

amugongol@gmail.com

LinkedIn: Mbangula GitHub: Mbangula

ORCID: 0000-0001-6468-2643

LANGUAGES

- ENGLISH Expert.
- OSHIWAMBO Mother tongue.
- AFRIKAANS Intermediate.
- **GERMAN** Advance beginner.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING:

• Python, MATLAB, C, Java, Android, C#, SQL, PL SQL, HTML.

DATABASE

• SQL Server, Oracle 9i/10/11g/12c, MySQL and Firebase.

STATISTICAL TOOLS

• R

SOFT-SKILLS

 Interpersonal skills, analytical skills and leadership.

MBANGULA AMUGONGO

ABOUT ME

Lameck Mbangula Amugongo holds a PhD from the University of Manchester, for his PhD he applied image-based data mining and artificial intelligence techniques to personalise treatment for lung cancer patients. He has a keen interest in quantitative research methods and their application to building responsible technology that solves societal problems. Moreover, Lameck is passionate about data science, technology policy and building ethical technology tools that make life easier for everyone.

EXPERIENCE

09/2022 - present

Associate Researcher, Institute of Ethics in Artificial Intelligence (Technische Universität München), Munich, Bavaria, Germany.

Working on an exciting project: MELISSA - mobile artificial intelligence solution for diabetes adaptive care.

- Investigating the ethical aspects related to trustworthy Al.
- Interdisciplinary research in ethics in artificial intelligence.
- Comprehensively address a growing group of ethical challenges arising at the interface of technology and human values.

07/2021 - present

Lecturer, Namibia University of Science & Technology, Windhoek Namibia

- Prepare and conduct lectures for artificial intelligence, data science and programming.
- Prepare student assessments, e.g. tests, projects and exams.
- Supervise student projects and conduct research.

(On Leave from 09/2021)

04/2018 - 06/2021

PhD Student, University of Manchester, UK Develop methods to describe, understand and predict lung tumour changes during RT using CBCTs.

- Create data pipelines and workflows.
- Develop a technique to investigate intensity changes across tumour-lung boundary.
- Develop a method to distinguish modes of tumour regression to determine the safety of RT adaptation.
- Develop models to proactively inform patients who will benefit from RT adaptation in lung cancer patients.

04/2014 - 01/2018

BI Analyst, Telecom Namibia, Windhoek Namibia

- Develop APEX application interfacing with Oracle databases.
- Perform data analysis on GSM trends.
- Develop interface between various systems.
- Maintain business intelligence tools, databases, dashboards, systems, or methods.
- Manage timely flow of business intelligence information to users.

HONORS & AWARDS

- Awarded best 3rd year Software Engineering student (2013).
- Best 4th Year Computer Science student (2015).
- National Commission of Research Science & Technology (NCRST) Youth Innovator (2015)
- Best Master's student in Computer Science (2017).
- Mandela Washington Fellow (MWF) 2017.
- 5th Heidelberg Laureate Forum (Young Researcher) 2017.

REFERENCES

1. Dr Colin Stanley

Executive Dean: Faculty of Computing & Informatics

Namibia University of Science &

Technology

Telephone Number: +264 61 206 4680

Email: cstanley@nust.na

2. Prof Juergen Sieck

Professor

Hochschule für Technik und Wirtschaft Berlin

Email: j.sieck@htw-berlin.de

3. Dr Alan McWilliam

Honorary Senior Lecturer University of Manchester Email:

alan.mcwilliam@manchester.ac.uk

4. Dr Eliana Vasquez Osorio

Senior Research Fellow

University of Manchester

Email: eliana.vasquezosorio@manches

ter.ac.uk

CONSULTANC

04/2016 - 04/2016

Consultant/Trainer, UNESCO Youth mobile training, Windhoek

- Equip 27 trainers with the technical and pedagogical skills to train young Namibians in mobile applications development.
- Training included: Object Oriented programming, Android development and app monetisation.

04/2018 - 06/2018

Lead country researcher (Namibia): Africa Open Data

Barometer, Local Deployment Research Institute (LDRI), Nairobi, Kenya

- Complete and/or update a number of questions on readiness, use and impacts of open data on the basis of desk research and interviews;
- Assess the availability of data through a number of checkpoints across selected categories;
- Provide quality brief justifications in English for each answer and detailed source information, along with a score and associated evidence to support that score;

EDUCATION

2018 - 2021

 Doctor of Philosophy in Cancer Science, University of Manchester.

2015 - 2017

 Master of Computer Science, Namibia University of Science & Technology (NUST).

2014 - 2014

 Bachelor computer science (Honours): Software Development, Polytechnic of Namibia.

2010 - 2013

 Bachelor of Information Technology in Software Engineering, Polytechnic of Namibia.

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- Identification of modes of tumour regression in NSCLC patients during radiotherapy. Med. Phys. (2021). https://doi.org/10.1002/mp.15320.
- Early prediction of tumour-response to radiotherapy in NSCLC patients. Physics in Medicine & Biology. (2021) https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1088/1361-6560/ac2f88.
- Identification of patterns of tumour change measured on CBCT images in NSCLC patients during radiotherapy. Physics in Medicine & Biology. (2020) https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1088/1361-6560/aba7d3.
- Understanding What Africans Say, Extended Abstracts of the 2018 CHI Conference, ACM, 10.1145/3170427.3180301, Montreal, Canada, 2018.
- Open Data Portal, a Technical Enabler to drive Innovation in Namibia, 2nd International Conference on Open and Big Data (OBD), IEEE, Vienna, Austria, 2016.
- Leveraging on open data to solve city challenges: A case study of Windhoek municipality, 3rd MEC International Conference on Big Data and Smart City (ICBDSC), IEEE, Muscat, Oman, 2016.